Papan Manna

Mobile Application Developer

Kolkata, West Bengal

L +91 6294284798

www.papanmanna.github.io

Professional Summary

Software Professional having 2+ years of experience software development including design, testing, release.

Experience in Android Application development using Java and Kotlin. Besides experiences on iOS development using Swift and XCode. Self motivated and fast learner and seeking a new opportunity that will allow me to further expand on these skills.

Work experience

Software Engineer

01-07-2018 - Present

Geotech Infoservices Pvt ltd.

Working in Geotech as an Android Application Developer. Besides I have Worked in all the phases of Development in various technology like Swift, React Native, Javascript, PHP, Symfony etc.

Trainee Software Engineer

01-02-2018 - 31-05-2018

Geotech Infoservices Pvt ltd

Learned the basic methodology of software development, work process and basic of many core technology like php, javascript, Ajax, jQuery etc.

Skills

Android

• Worked with various architectures e.g. MVC, MVP, MVVM, MVI etc.

- Used and aware of many modern and widely used libraries and tools like ViewModel, LiveData, Room Database, Data/View Binding.
- Work Manager and many more JetPack components.

- Used RxJava in multiple projects.
- Getting old school and using Service for background processing.

Core Java

Have knowledge and experience on

- OOPS concepts.
- Collection framework.
- Generics.
- Exception Handling.
- Multi threading.
- AWT and Swing etc.

Kotlin

• Well aware of most of the advanced features introduced in Kotlin including Coroutine, Extension Functions, Sealed Class, Lambda, Lambda Extension, Local Function, Higher Order Functions etc.

Date:

Have knowledge and experience on

• UIKit, Core Data, Foundation, JavaScriptCore, MapKit, Network, Swift, XCode etc.

(Signature)

Education	
B.Tech in Computer Science And Engineering	2014 - 2018
Meghnad Saha Institute Of Technology	
I have complete my B.Tech degree with 86% marks	
Higher Secondary Education	2012 - 2014
Midnapore Colligiate School	
I have scored 84% in higher secondary	
Secondary Education	2007 - 2012
Akchara Desh Bondhu High School	
I have scored 86% in secondary exam	
Projects	
Please visit my github page to look at my works.	
https://papanmanna.github.io/	
Declare	
	Papan Manna